all right so hope in 19 is happening we
have a pandemic and it is showing the
cracks in our society cracks that I have
already know are there welcome to the
party welcome to what we can now do to
solve it so our health care system is
not great it's not designed to have
problem solving doctors who can think
outside the box it's designed to be the
exact opposite of that for them to
listen to the higher-ups to be like well
there was no memo on it so it can't be
that that's the case what I propose is
that we look at our medical system look
what's going wrong as it's going wrong
come up with solutions to both get sick
people through this but also to stop the
next pandemic and just realize that our
healthcare system is not there to keep
us healthy or get us back to health it's
actually there to get a profit for the
people who get profit from there and
that comes with a real cost to human
lives
we could have systems in place to share
information but because of proprietary
nough still want to make money
we aren't designed to be that open we
need to be open in this world of global
movement of people we also need global
movement of information needs to be
accessible to everyone we are
governments I don't have enough
information to act again they don't have
information on the supply chain they
don't have information on the healthcare
their name information on the actual
virus itself or how its transmitted or
they don't know what's true and what's
not true and they know that any time
they're gonna have top-down force or
even top-down suggestions it's gonna be
met with tension from Authority right I
feel tension when my government tells me
to do something if we were like let's
all self quarantine I had say we might
want our governments to shut certain
things down but also then they're forced
to do things like shut down schools when
it's we haven't shown that that actually
has a direct impact on not transmitting
the virus and who's gonna take care of
the nurses children especially the
nurses
who don't make enough to pay someone to
come and look after their kids but their
kids are in school their kids are in
daycare and they won't be in when we
shut those down we can recreate society
in a way that's more insulated that
isn't huge mega cities that everyone's
all traipsing about the globe all the
time we need to know that this is this
is going to happen in the future and how
do we keep people safe there should be
screening and fevers on every plane that
gets off everywhere should be like how
are we screened going on because I might
carry a hundred milliliters or more of
liquid but not when were disease vectors
like we have to have systems in place
unless they're from the bottom up or
we've requested these things the
businesses and the government's don't
have the incentive to create them and so
that is why we need a system to be able
to bring people together to say what is
the best way to combat global illness
with air travel is probably having
systems in place to stop people who are
sick getting on the plane and definitely
getting off the plane businesses how the
current market is set up is it pays
people incentivizes people who have high
risk tolerance and people with high risk
tolerance create things that aren't as
robust as people with low risk tolerance
but you can't compete in the marketplace
if you have low risk tolerance so we are
gonna see a lot of businesses collapse
because they are started by
entrepreneurs who are flying by the seat
of their pants
I'm just like I'll figure it out when I
get there think it's Ella make it we
need a new way to get the best ideas and
the best inventions out into the world
without it needing to go through the
marketplace bringing the risk down for
the person inventing it and sharing in
that risk truly including sharing in the
reward and so there are many things we
need a media source that we can actually
trust that can disseminate information
in a way that's usable and trustworthy
and you can see where it came from and
why it's there and updated as we go and
one source so that we can keep referring
back to it and it's not
the rumor mill that somehow our media
reports on and there aren't any more
reporters and no one listens to
scientists but they want them to give
news we just there our system is complex
and we have to be able to create
solutions together that we all can get
behind meaning a voluntary enticing
solution like if you need to do self
quarantine for 14 days and you're not
gonna do it why how can we help you do
it
and so that is today's video I hope it
wasn't just too much of a downer I'd
hate to try to keep recording it to
bring a little more energy to it it
wasn't like doom and gloom but I lived
in doom and gloom for decades I know
what's coming
and so I also know how to solve it and
humanity doesn't know being hungry being
scared does not bring out our best so we
need to be able to solve these problems
when we're healthy and when we're
incentivize but not terrified thank you
please like and subscribe and bite your
friends let's create a world that works
during this time Demick